

Florent Clarret

Software engineer

+33 (0)6 62 97 01 69 florent.clarret@gmail.com florent-clarret iii FlorentClarret ?

Software engineer who has been working on backends for 6 years. Love automating tasks to make the processes faster and easier for me and my team. Always willing to learn new things, I also like to share my knowledge with others.

Languages

Coding skills

Django

Java

French English

Experience

Since 2020 Backend software engineer

Geovelo, Tours

- · Backend lead developer of the mobile application for cyclists Geovelo
- · Solution developed in Python with the django framework relying on multiple PostgreSQL databases
- Occasionally working on the route planner in C++ when the team needs a hand
- Application deployed in production using Docker in a Kubernetes cluster, monitored with prometheus and grafana
- · Continuous integration pipelines setup with Gitlab, added unit tests, automated repetitive tasks as much as possible. I also wrote a set of tools to make our development process smoother
- · Production monitoring and support. Intervention in case of problem, even outside the backend perimeter

Since 2019 Backend mentor

OpenClassrooms, Remote

- Mentor on both java and python backend paths for the OpenClassrooms online teaching platform
- Accompany students on their journey to become software developers

Tooling



2017 - 2020 Teacher

Polytech Tours, Tours

- · Teacher at the Polytech Tours engineering school for 64h per years
- · Development in java focused on optimization, benchmarking, identifying bottlenecks, best practices, debugging and improving applications

2018 - 2020 Backend software engineer

- · Maintained, developed and optimized a strong authentication solution backend
- Developed in Java with Spring Boot and relying on MySQL databases
- Dockerize the application for ease of testing. Set up the continuous integration pipelines with Gitlab and wrote the complete tests suite
- Production support, monitoring with splunk

#Homelab #DIY #AutomateBoringStuff

Hobbies

Walking

Reading

Side projects 2015 - 2018 Backend software engineer

Worldline, Tours

- Developed, optimized and deployed into production the new backend version for Worldline's payment service provider
- · Backend written in Java, deployed with JBoss or Tomcat and working with Oracle and MySQL databases
- Lead on the platform migration in production and production support. Platform monitored with elasticsearch, logstash and kibana
- · Maintained the first version of the backend mostly written in C, Sybase SQL stored procedures, Awk and Shell scripts
- · Worked with international teams based in India and Armenia

Polytech Tours, Tours

· Customized courses for the first year students focused on algorithmic, data structure and on the C language

Education

2013 - 2015 Teacher

2012 - 2015 Engineering degree in computer science

Polytech Tours, Tours

IUT, Lens

2010 - 2012 Diplôme universitaire de technologie in computer science